<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>golang on Edmonton Go</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/tags/golang/</link><description>Recent content in golang on Edmonton Go</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edmontongo.org/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February 2022 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2022-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2022-02/</guid><description>Meetup #74. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Online Meeting at 6:30pm MST.
Agenda Go 1.18 New Feature: Generics Peter Preeper reviews new awaited feature of Generics
Future Topics Discussion Open discussion on topic for future talks, workshops, activities.
News golangweekly.com latest Articles &amp;amp; Resources What&amp;rsquo;s Coming in Go 1.18 Video: Getting Started with Generics in Go Go Generics for the Busy Gopher Events Edmonton Go Meetup - March</description></item><item><title>April 2021 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-04/</guid><description>Meetup #73. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Talks Google Cloud Functions Matthias Stone will be presenting on basic practices of creating Google Cloud Functions in Go. (slides)
News Golang Weekly Edmonton Go Meetup - February 2022</description></item><item><title>February 2021 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-02/</guid><description>Meetup #71. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Error Handling discussion Peter Preeper will be walking us through the changes to the errors package introduced in Go 1.13. We&amp;rsquo;ll be watching Can We Panic Yet? Error Handling in Go as a group. Discussion to follow. News Go 1.16 is released Golang Weekly Events Edmonton Go Meetup - April</description></item><item><title>January 2021 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-01/</guid><description>Meetup #70. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Talks Four Go-to Packages Matthias Stone (slides)
Open Mic Anyone can feel free to share something they are working on or learning that is related to the Go programming language.
News GopherCon 2020 videos Can We Panic Yet? Error Handling in Go Command PATH security in Go A Proposal for Adding Generics to Go Go on ARM and Beyond Golang Weekly Events Edmonton Go Meetup - February</description></item><item><title>November 2020 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-11/</guid><description>Meetup #69
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Open Mic Anyone can feel free to share something they are working on or learning that is related to the Go programming language.
News Eleven Years of Go Talks Edmonton Go Meetup - January</description></item><item><title>October 2020 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-10/</guid><description>Meetup #68
We will be meeting online this month. Currently planning on using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MDT, if that changes expect an update here and on Twitter.
Talks CLI tools with OAuth Matthias Stone
News GopherCon 2020 is entirely virtual (GoVirCon!) Events Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>September 2020 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-09/</guid><description>Meetup #67.
We will be meeting in person at Startup Edmonton at 6:30 pm. Capacity is limited to 15 people.
Pre-registration is required. Please RSVP by emailing gopher@nathany.com to be added as a visitor. You will receive a link which includes COVID-19 pre-screening questions. Please note that registration at Meetup is not sufficient.
Masks are required. Please maintain physical distance while in the space. Hand sanitizer is provided.
Please have dinner before coming as no food will be provided.</description></item><item><title>March 2020 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-03/</guid><description>Meetup #66. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online at 6:30 pm. Live stream
Talks Prometheus Brandon Glowatski
News Go 1.14 released (release notes) Go 1.14.1 Polyglot YEG cancelled Startup Edmonton closed to the public Events Edmonton Go Meetup - September</description></item><item><title>February 2020 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-02/</guid><description>Meetup #65. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get going at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton
Video State of Go 2020 News Go 1.14 RC1 (release notes) Golang Weekly Black Hat Go (book) Events Monthly Hack Day - Mar 14 Polyglot YEG - Apr 4 Edmonton Go Meetup - March</description></item><item><title>January 2020 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2020-01/</guid><description>Meetup #64. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get going at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton
Talks Profiling with pprof Matthias Stone
News Go 1.14 Beta 1 Go 1.13.7 security update Events Monthly Hack Day - Feb 1 Polyglot YEG - Apr 4 Edmonton Go Meetup - February</description></item><item><title>November 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-11/</guid><description>Meetup #63. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get going at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton
Talks Video: Go Module Proxy: Life of a Query by Katie Hockman News Go Turns 10 Go.dev Announcing the 2019 Go Developer Survey Events Monthly Hack Day - Dec 7 Edmonton Go Meetup - January</description></item><item><title>October 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-10/</guid><description>Meetup #62. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get going at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton
Food by Improbable (after the talk)
Talks Introduction to gRPC Scott Brooks
Events Monthly Hack Day - Nov 2 Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>September 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-09/</guid><description>Meetup #61. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks What&amp;#39;s New in Go 1.13 Matthias Stone (slides)
Challengs Bring a laptop or a friend with a laptop You should install Go before arriving We will be pair programming so experience with Go is optional See the slides News Go 1.13 Go 1.13.1 - Sep 25 Module Mirror and Checksum Database Launched Unit Testing Code with Hard-to-Mock Dependencies by Adam Wolfe Gordon GopherCon 2019 talks Events Monthly Hack Day - Oct 5 Hacktoberfest Kickoff - Oct 7 Edmonton Startup Week - Oct 21-25 Canada Learning Code: YEGTech Open House - Oct 26 Edmonton Go Meetup - October</description></item><item><title>May 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-05/</guid><description>Meetup #60. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Go Func Yourself! A brief introduction to serverless Go Matthias Stone (slides)
News Go 1.12.5 and Go 1.11.10 Events Monthly Hack Day - Jun 1 Polyglot YYC - Jun 2, Calgary Gocon Canada - May 31, Toronto GopherCon - Jul 24-27, San Diego Edmonton Go Meetup - September</description></item><item><title>April 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-04/</guid><description>Meetup #59. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Activities Go and Docker Peter Preeper (code)
Deployment Discussion Deployment Discussion: All attendees will be invited to share their experience with deploying Go services.
Video Video: Either Errors in Go 2 by Marcel Van Lohuizen, or Absolute Unit (Test) by Dave Cheney.
News Go 2018 Survey Results Events Monthly Hack Day - May 4 Gocon Canada - May 31, Toronto GopherCon - Jul 24-27, San Diego Edmonton Go Meetup - May</description></item><item><title>March 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-03/</guid><description>Meetup #58. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Functional Go: How well does Go Support Functional Programming? Axel von Bertoldi (slides)
News Gopherbot Using Go Modules Debugging what you deploy in Go 1.12 Events Monthly Hack Day - Apr 6 Gocon Canada - May 31, Toronto GopherCon - Jul 24-27, San Diego Edmonton Go Meetup - April</description></item><item><title>February 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-02/</guid><description>Meetup #58. Please RSVP at Meetup.
Talks The February meetup is cancelled. Talks The State of Go: What&amp;rsquo;s New Since Go 1.10 by Francesc Campoy Talks Monthly Hack Day - Mar 2 Edmonton Go Meetup - March</description></item><item><title>January 2019 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2019-01/</guid><description>Meetup #57. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Go and Node.js: A comparison Nathan Youngman (slides, code)
News Go 1.11.5 and 1.10.8 have been released! Go 1.12 Beta 2 is released (draft release notes) Go Modules in 2019 Our Software Dependency Problem by Russ Cox Jobs Go developer at CleanNow Events Monthly Hack Day - Feb 2 Polyglot YEG - Feb 9 Edmonton Go Meetup - February</description></item><item><title>November 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-11/</guid><description>Meetup #56. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
News Go User Survey Nine years of Go Go 2 Draft Specifications by Rob Pike (video) Transition to Go 2 by Ian Lance Taylor (video) GopherCon EU 2018 talks Intro to Go Modules and SemVer by Francesc Campoy (video) Talks Go and A.I. Matthias Stone GitHub and RL Book</description></item><item><title>Go for Web Developers Workshop Part II</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-10-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-10-22/</guid><description>Meetup #55. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Workshop Instructor: Chris Olsen
Bring a laptop with Go installed. Slides from the workshop News All About Go video with Francesc Campoy GothamGo videos Gopherpalooza videos LondonGophers videos The Past, Present, and Future of Go 2 slides by Dave Cheney GolangShow Episode 127 compSci.Now() Episode 1 Announcing App Engine’s New Go 1.</description></item><item><title>Go for Web Developers Workshop Part I</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-10-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-10-15/</guid><description>Meetup #54. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:00 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Workshop Instructor: Nathan Youngman
Mentors: Chris Olsen, Peter Preeper
We&amp;rsquo;ll be working on a client for a JSON API. Bring a laptop with Go installed. Slides from the workshop Events Edmonton Go: Go for Web Developers Workshop Part II - October 22 Hacktoberfest - Oct 15, 22, 29 GoLab in Florence, Italy - Oct 22-23 Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>September 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-09/</guid><description>Meetup #53. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Unit Testing Code with Hard-to-Mock Dependencies Adam Wolfe Gordon (slides pdf)
News GopherCon UK videos GopherCon videos Mile High Gophers videos GopherCon Europe videos Go 2 Draft Designs Writing a Compiler in Go by Thorsten Ball Get Programming with Go by Nathan Youngman and Roger Peppé Events Monthly Hack Day - Oct 13 (tech t-shirt and sticker exchange) Startup Week - Oct 15-19 Hacktoberfest - Oct 15, 22, 29 GoLab in Florence, Italy - Oct 22-23 Edmonton Go: Go for Web Developers Workshop Part I - Oct 15 (Startup Week Schedule) Edmonton Go: Go for Web Developers Workshop Part II - Oct 22 Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>August 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-08/</guid><description>Meetup #52. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Talks Go modules quick overview Peter Preeper (slides)
News &amp;amp; Articles Go 1.11 is released (release notes) Go Northwest videos Events GopherCon - Aug 27-30 Monthly Hack Day - Sep 8 Startup Week - Oct 15-19 (workshop) Edmonton Go Meetup - September (talk)</description></item><item><title>July 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-07/</guid><description>Meetup #51. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Hugo Tidbits Anthony Fok
Behind the scenes with a contributor to Hugo.
What&amp;#39;s new in Hugo Nathan Youngman (slides)
Hugo is a static site generator useful for blogs, marketing websites, and so on. We&amp;rsquo;ll take a quick look at Hugo Pipes, the new asset pipeline, and how it simplifies deployment.</description></item><item><title>June 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-06/</guid><description>Meetup #50. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Discussion The Impact of Community by Cassandra Salisbury (video)
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the Go Community. The Community Outreach Working Group (discussion), Startup Week Community Event (Oct 15-19), Go adoption in Edmonton, and our meetup. (slides)
Jobs Software Engineer at CenturyLink Events Monthly Hack Day - Jul 7 GopherCon UK - Aug 1-3 (scholarships) GopherCon - Aug 27-30 (scholarships) Edmonton Go Meetup - July</description></item><item><title>May 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-05/</guid><description>Meetup #49. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Discussion Versioning in Go The vgo proposal is accepted. Now what? by Russ Cox Failure Modes by Sam Boyer Go: From Godep To vgo, A Commentated History by Matt Farina Go vgo: A Broken Dependency Tree by Matt Farina Go vgo: Semantic Versioning and Human Error by Matt Farina An Analysis of vgo by Sam Boyer (reddit | hn) The Principles of Versioning in Go (video) Dependencies and the future of Go (podcast) A Proposal for Package Versioning in Go proposal: add package version support to Go toolchain Thoughts on vgo and dep by Sam Boyer Building Predictability into Your Pipeline with Russ Cox, Jess Frazelle, Sam Boyer and Pete Garcin (video) Go &amp;amp; Versioning by Russ Cox The New Era of Go Package Management by Sam Boyer (video) Version SAT by Russ Cox dep Go Package Management (Google Group) News Go&amp;rsquo;s New Brand GopherCon Scholarships (Women Who Go) Events Monthly Hack Day - Jun 2 Exchange.</description></item><item><title>April 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-04/</guid><description>Meetup #48. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Meet Hugo the Static Site Generator Tammy Lee (slides)
EdmontonGo.org behind the scenes: a website built with Hugo Nathan Youngman (code)
Jobs Software Engineering Intern, Consul (remote) DigitalOcean we love go Go Jobs &amp;amp; Developers How engineers can stand out from the applicant pool News Interactive Go Programming with Jupyter (source) Go Time podcast Golang Weekly Giving Ashley McNamara After Care Women Who Go threads GopherCon Diversity Scholarship Donations Events GothamGo - Apr 27 Monthly Hack Day - May 5 GopherCon UK - Aug 1-3 (scholarships) GopherCon - Aug 27-30 Edmonton Go Meetup - May</description></item><item><title>March 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-03/</guid><description>Meetup #47. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks An Introduction to Testing with External Services Matthias Stone
News A Proposal for Package Versioning in Go Events Monthly Hack Day - Apr 7 GopherCon - Aug 27-30 Edmonton Go Meetup - April</description></item><item><title>February 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-02/</guid><description>Meetup #46. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Lightning Talks Automate Git Repository Bisection with Go Test by Peter Preeper (slides) Coding Practice Bring a laptop and/or a friend. We will be working in teams, so deep experience with Go is not required.
Install Go on your laptop in advance or use The Go Playground.
News Go 1.</description></item><item><title>January 2018 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2018-01/</guid><description>Meetup #45. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Functional Options Pattern Adam Wolfe Gordon (slides)
To err is human Nathan Youngman (slides)
Jobs Software Developer at Tendermint (Toronto) News Go 1.9.3 Go 1.10 beta 2 What&amp;rsquo;s new in Go 1.10 Go Support for AWS Lambda Twirp RPC framework from Twitch Golang Weekly GopherAcademy Advent 2017 series Events Monthly Hack Day - Jan 13 Monthly Hack Day - Feb 3 GopherCon - Aug 27-30 Edmonton Go Meetup - February</description></item><item><title>November 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-11/</guid><description>Meetup #44. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Concurrency in Go: An Introduction to Channels Tobias Renwick (code)
News Participate in the 2017 Go User Survey Eight years of Go The new pprof user interface Events Monthly Hack Day - Dec 2 Edmonton Go Meetup - January</description></item><item><title>September 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-09/</guid><description>Meetup #43. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks My first three months with Go Brett Anderson (slides)
gotest in color Peter Preeper (slides)
News Go: Ten years and climbing by Rob Pike Golang Conference UK 2017 videos go test with colors by JBD The new kid in town — Go&amp;rsquo;s sync.Map by Ralph Caraveo III Events Monthly Hack Day - Oct 14 Startup Week Edmonton - Oct 16 - 20 Hacktoberfest - Oct 23 Edmonton Go Hacktoberfest Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>August 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-08/</guid><description>Meetup #42. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Intro to database/sql Nicholas Boers (slides, code)
Test Helper Functions Adam Wolfe Gordon
vendor/... James Bell
News &amp;amp; Articles Go 1.9 is released Go 1.9 Release Party GoSF (video) Go 1.9 Release Party (slides) by Dave Cheney Cute Gophers (plushies) Events Monthly Hack Day - Sep 9 Edmonton Go Meetup - September</description></item><item><title>July 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-07/</guid><description>Meetup #41. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Activities GopherCon recap News GopherCon videos, lightning talks, slides, and liveblog. Toward Go 2 Go experience report: the append function Should Go 2.0 support generics? TIOBE: Go language at all time high and in the top 10 Go 1.9 comes to 64-bit ARM Abundant concurrency in Go Hyperproductive development Jobs Local Web Developer at Beamdog (JavaScript, Ruby) DevOps Engineer at Beamdog (Chef, AWS) Web Developer at Paper Leaf (WordPress, Frontend) .</description></item><item><title>June 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-06/</guid><description>Meetup #40. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Talks Structured logging Adam Wolfe Gordon (slides PDF, code)
Effective error handling Gerrit Renker (slides)
News Go 1.9 beta 2 Go 1.9 draft release notes What’s new in Google’s Go 1.9 language InfoWorld Web Development with Go Jonathan Calhoun Ultimate Go Programming LiveLessons William Kennedy Events GopherCon July 12-15 Edmonton Go Meetup - July</description></item><item><title>May 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-05/</guid><description>Meetup #39. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Code Generation Gerrit Renker (slides)
dep Nathan Youngman (slides)
Activities Kick the tires on dep, now that the manifest files are considered stable. Bring your laptop and a Go project if you have one. Events Monthly Hack Day - Jun 3 GopherCon July 12-15 Edmonton Go Meetup - June</description></item><item><title>GopherFest 2017</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-gopherfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-gopherfest/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 7:00 pm.
NOTE: Please try to arrive before 7:30, as the doors will be locked after 7:30 pm. If you arrive late, ask to be let in.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Snacks sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks We will be streaming the GopherFest 2017 event live from San Francisco.
7:00 Socialize (snacks provided) 7:55 Live streaming begins in the Program Room 10:00 Talks wrap up State of Go Francesc Campoy Flores</description></item><item><title>April 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-04/</guid><description>Meetup #38. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Talks Diet Hacks Nathan Youngman (slides)
Reactive Programming in Go Gerrit Renker (slides)
Events DemoCamp 36 - May 2 Monthly Hack Day - May 6 GopherCon July 12-15 Edmonton Go Meetup - May</description></item><item><title>March 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-03/</guid><description>Meetup #37. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Goroutines An introduction to goroutines by Nathan Youngman (slides).
Un-Paralleled Concurrency Introduction to concurrency patterns in Go by Gerrit Renker (slides).
Gotrace Concurrency tracer and visualizer (source) demonstration by Matthias Stone
The atomic package Atomic memory primitives by Lukasz Rozycki (slides).
News Women Who Go to GopherCon fundraiser WWG Gophercon Scholarship Events Monthly Hack Day - April 1 GopherCon July 12-15 Edmonton Go Meetup - April</description></item><item><title>February 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-02/</guid><description>Meetup #36. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Plugins Grant Hunter, voiced by Brett McKay and Stefan Martynkiw (code)
HTTP Server Graceful Shutdown Lukasz Rozycki (slides)
The default GOPATH Rebecca Walton (slides)
sort.Slice James Bell (code)
database/sql context Matthias Stone (slides)
What&amp;#39;s Next for Go Nathan Youngman (slides)
News Gopherize.me avatar generator Go 1.</description></item><item><title>January 2017 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2017-01/</guid><description>Meetup #35. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Interfaces in Go Brett McKay is speaking about interfaces in Go (slides).
Protocol Buffers and gRPC in Go Adam Wolfe Gordon is presenting Protocol Buffers and gRPC in Go. (slides, code)
News Go 1.8 Release Candidate 2 Go 1.8 draft release notes The Saga of Go Dependency Management Buffalo web development eco-system Events Web Development with Buffalo - Jan 31 at noon MST Rapid Web Development with Buffalo and Ponzu - Feb 2 at 11am MST Monthly Hack Day - Feb 4 Edmonton Go Meetup - February GopherCon July 12-15</description></item><item><title>November 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-11/</guid><description>Meetup #34. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Reasons to read The Go Programming Language Jordan Torbiak (slides)
The Go Programming Language provides great value as a reference in general and in particular for testing and reflection, as a collection of interesting exercises in a reasonable order, and as a comprehensive textbook after more introductory material like the Tour and Effective Go.</description></item><item><title>October 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-10/</guid><description>Meetup #33. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Barrier Pattern in Go (with Context) Gerrit Renker (slides)
Video: Idiomatic Go Tricks Mat Ryer (video, slides)
News Go 1.7.3 released dotGo videos are being posted Go 1.8 compiler is 12% faster (so far) Events Monthly Hack Day - Nov 5 Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>September 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-09/</guid><description>Meetup #32. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Food sponsored by Bellstone Engineering.
Talks Using Rust Grant Hunter shares his experience (code).
Using Rust on Habitat Fletcher Nichol shares his experience using Rust to work on Habitat over the last year.
News Golang UK videos are out Rust Conf videos (coming soon) Events Monthly Hack Day - Oct 1 Edmonton Go Meetup - October</description></item><item><title>August 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-08/</guid><description>Meetup #31. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Movie Night We watched two talks from GopherCon 2016:
Navigating Unfamiliar Code with the Go Guru Navigating Unfamiliar Code with the Go Guru (slides) by Alan Donovan
Go for Data Science Go for Data Science (slides) by Daniel Whitenack
News Go 1.7 released (slides) GopherCon 2016 videos (slides) State of Go 2016 survey results by Edward Muller Just for Func video series by Francesc Campoy Proposal: sort: make sorting easier (Go 1.</description></item><item><title>July 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-07/</guid><description>Meetup #30. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Discussion There are no formal presentations this month. We have room for a small group in Meeting Room #1 and can enjoy pizza, discussions, and show and tell.
News &amp;amp; Articles Go 1.7 Release Candidate 3 GopherCon 2016 - Retrospective by Erik St. Martin and Brian Ketelsen GopherCon 2016 - Talks Go is for everyone by Matt Aimonetti Go Time podcast CryptoPasta by George Tankersley Events Monthly Hack Day - August 6th Edmonton Go Meetup - August</description></item><item><title>June 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-06/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Food provided by Bellstone Engineering.
Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Talks BYOC (Bring Your Own Code) We are encouraging attendees to bring a small Go code sample that they&amp;rsquo;ve written and would like to share. We plan to break into small groups to discuss and learn together. Consider things you have written that you found neat, challenging, or are proud of.</description></item><item><title>May 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-05/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Food provided by Bellstone Engineering.
Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Talks Google App Engine Chris Olsen will be sharing what he has learned about using Google App Engine. (slides)
Stateful Messaging Gerrit Renker will be talking about stateful messaging (aka &amp;ldquo;Scalability Protocols&amp;rdquo;) using go-mangos. (slides, demo code)
Events Monthly Hack Day - June 4 (Registration required) GopherCon 2016 Kickoff Party - July 10 GopherCon July 11-13 Edmonton Go Meetup - June</description></item><item><title>April 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-04/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Food provided by Bellstone Engineering.
Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Talks Testing concurrent things Matthias Stone - Slides
Events Monthly Hack Day - April 2 (Registration required) Edmonton Go Meetup - May</description></item><item><title>March 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-03/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get things started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Food provided by Bellstone Engineering.
Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
eBook Giveaway from Manning Publications:
Generative Art by Matt Pearson Grokking Algorithms by Aditya Y. Bhargava Learn Go by Nathan Youngman Talks Shopping is hard, let&amp;#39;s build a web app Chris Olsen will touch on many of the things that are required to create a working web application in Go.</description></item><item><title>February 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-02/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get things started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Food provided by Bellstone Engineering.
Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
eBook Giveaway from Manning Publications:
Go in Practice by Matt Butcher and Matt Farina MongoDB in Action, Second Edition by Kyle Banker, Peter Bakkum, Shaun Verch, Douglas Garrett, and Tim Hawkins Redis in Action by Josiah Carlson Talks Go 1.6 was released on February 17th.</description></item><item><title>January 2016 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-01/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
We get things started at 6:30 pm.
Sponsors Pizza provided by Bellstone Engineering and they&amp;rsquo;re hiring. Venue provided by Startup Edmonton.
Manning Publications eBook Giveaway:
Go Web Programming by Sau Sheong Chang Algorithms of the Intelligent Web, Second Edition by Douglas G. McIlwraith, Haralambos Marmanis, and Dmitry Babenko Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja, Second Edition by John Resig, Bear Bibeault, and Josip Maras News Go 1.</description></item><item><title>Gopher Gala 2016</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-gala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2016-gala/</guid><description>Registration Gopher Gala is a distributed hackathon happening January 22-24 (registration is required).
Please RSVP at Meetup if you are joining us at Startup Edmonton. Snacks and beverages will be provided.
Optionally sign up for the Gopher team on Slack and join the #edmontongo channel for communication before and during the event.
Schedule Friday 6pm - 10pm The hackathon starts at 6pm. Come early to find your team members and get ready.</description></item><item><title>Two Year Recap</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/recap/</guid><description>Two years ago Edmonton Go was just an idea. Thanks to Startup Edmonton for generously providing the space, and to Daniel Huckstep for the requisite kick-in-the-pants, January 27, 2014 marked our first meetup.
Together we&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed talks, discussions, code reading, hack nights, videos, workshops, cake eating, sphero battles, and other activities. A dozen people delivered 34 talks, sharing their knowledge and experience with everyone. Thank you so much for your contribution!</description></item><item><title>November 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-11/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Food at 6:30 pm. News and Talks at 6:45.
eBook Giveaway: R in Action, Second Edition, Unity in Action and Go in Action
Talks Messaging patterns and job queues in Go Gerrit Renker (pdf slides)
The Legacy of Go Dave Cheney (video)
News Six years of Go Go Community Code of Conduct GothamGo videos Alan Donovan and Brian Kernighan Answer Your Questions dotGo photos (videos coming soon) Go Proverbs from GopherFest SV Events Monthly Hack Day - December 5 (Registration required) Gopher Gala - January 22-24 (Registration required) Edmonton Go Meetup - January</description></item><item><title>October 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-10/</guid><description> Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Food at 6:30 pm. News and Talks at 6:45.
eBook Giveaway: jQuery in Action, Third Edition and Learn Go
Talks The `go present` tool Matthias Stone
Stupid Gopher Tricks Andrew Gerrand (video and discussion)
Books &amp;amp; Resources The Go Programming Language by Alan A. A. Donovan and Brian W. Kernighan Go in Action by William Kennedy with Brian Ketelsen and Erik St. Martin Learn Go by Nathan Youngman Events Edmonton Startup Week - October 19-22 Monthly Hack Day and Code Retreat - November 7 (RSVP required) Edmonton Go Meetup - November</description></item><item><title>September 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-09/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Food at 6:30 pm, sponsored by Bellstone.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Talks gorename - how the sausage is made Matthias Stone (slides)
Embedding Go into C Scott Brooks
News and Articles Inside Go Go 1.5.1 released Proposal: Rules for passing pointers between Go and C html/template {{block}} syntax for Go 1.6 (example) net/http2 moved, work resumes Community Announcing: The Go Forum What Golang UK Taught Me About Community Golang UK Conference videos Go Adoption Otto: the successor to Vagrant (from HashiCorp) Keybase command line beta (was JavaScript) Go at Basecamp by Noah Lorang Sorry, Ruby — I think I’ve fallen for Go!</description></item><item><title>August 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-08/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Talks Introduction to Reflection Nicholas Boers (slides)
Software Defined Networking Gerrit Renker and Curtis Collicutt
What&amp;#39;s New in Go 1.5 Matthias Stone
News and Articles Go 1.5 is released (release notes) Google&amp;rsquo;s In-House Programming Language Now Runs on Phones Wired Cross compilation with Go 1.5 Online Talks GopherCon 2015 Roundup (videos, lightning talk videos) Stupid Gopher Tricks by Andrew Gerrand (Golang UK) Learning Resources Mark Bates on Go Core Techniques and Tools Events Monthly Hack Day September 12 (RSVP required) Edmonton Go Meetup - September</description></item><item><title>July 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-07/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Talks GopherCon recap slides
Command line user interfaces Gerrit Renker
News GopherCon live blog Go 1.5 beta App Engine for Go is Generally Available Go support now official on Heroku Articles How We Moved Our API From Ruby to Go and Saved Our Sanity by Charity Majors (Parse) The RedMonk Programming Language Rankings: June 2015 (up two spots to #15) Who is the Go Developer?</description></item><item><title>June 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-06/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Talks Packer Packer is a tool building machine images written in Go. Our resident devops guru, Fletcher Nichol, from Chef Software will be presenting on it.
See also: images
Code reading Back by popular demand, we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a code reading activity in small groups.
Some suggestions:
container/heap is a [heap data structure](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heap_(data_structure) interface provided by the Go standard library negroni is a middleware stack for Go (interpose is an alternative) gorilla/pat is a request router, and much simpler than gorilla/mux gorilla/context is a registry for request variables News GopherFest 2015 videos Go Team is working on a Code of Conduct, likely derived from Django Change Proposal Process for Go (mailing list) and Interim Code Review and Issue Tracker Conventions GO15VENDOREXPERIMENT=1 Go Newsletter and @EdmontonGo for more news Events GopherCon 2015 - July 8-9 at the Colorado Convention Center Edmonton Go Meetup - July</description></item><item><title>May 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-05/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Lightning Talks Short ~10 minute talks on Go or something you&amp;rsquo;re using Go for.
Dockerize Go and Redis Chris Olsen (source)
Testing in Go Matthias Stone
Go Arrays &amp;amp; Slices Nathan Youngman (slides)
News Introducing gb, a project based build tool for the Go programming language by Dave Cheney (getgb.io) go-bootstrap, default web project. Events Monthly Hack Day - May 13 GopherCon 2015 - July 8-9 at the Colorado Convention Center Edmonton Go Meetup - June</description></item><item><title>April 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-04/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Talks Running MongoDB Queries Concurrently With Go William Kennedy will be presenting (via Google Hangout) on using MongoDB and the mgo library (pronounced &amp;ldquo;mango&amp;rdquo;) for Go.
News GopherCon Speakers &amp;amp; Talks Announced Go 1.5 To Do List Articles and Talks Interview with Go’s Russ Cox and Sameer Ajmani More Research Problems of Implementing Go by Dmitry Vyukov Building Database Driven Apps With Go by Anna Navatsyk Events Monthly Hackathon - April 11 Docker&amp;rsquo;s Birthday Party March 23-April 19 Go Challenge - Monthly GopherCon 2015 - July 8-9 at the Colorado Convention Center Edmonton Go Meetup - May</description></item><item><title>March 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-03/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
News and Talks at 6:45.
Talks Interactive Discussion Matthias Stone will be leading a discussion on how to use Go to develop web services. Bring your questions and experiences.
GopherCon India Video Antendees will vote on a short list of videos from GopherCon India, and the winner will be shown.
News Two Go Developers Who Switched from JavaScript and Ruby by The New Stack Why Timehop Chose Go to Replace Our Rails App by Benny Wong Announcing MongoDB 3.</description></item><item><title>February 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-02/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Talks at 7:00.
Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Talks Go and Databases Brett McKay (slides)
News Go 1.4.2 Hugo 0.13.0 Go in Go (dev.cc merged to master, docs) Building Microservices by Sam Newman Trumpet in Calgary, AB is hiring for Go and C/C++ Gift (Gopher Gala) by Scott Brooks Edmonton Go is looking for sponsors for food Articles and Talks The State of Go by Andrew Gerrand Interview: Gopher Andrew Gerrand GopherCon India Live Blog Events Go Challenge - March 1-15 Startup Weekend EDU - March 6-8 - Early Bird Tickets $75 Monthly Hackathon - March 14 Polyglot AB - March 28 in Calgary GopherCon 2015 - July 8-9 at the Colorado Convention Center Edmonton Go Meetup - March</description></item><item><title>January 2015 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2015-01/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Talks at 7:00.
Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Talks Amazon S3 with Go Nathan Youngman (s3up source)
Error Handling In Go William Kennedy (GothamGo video, slides)
News Go 1.4.1 release GopherCon 2015 Tickets Available GopherCon 2015 Call for Proposals Go Newsletter 41, now published by Cooper Press. Improvements on gopkg.in by Gustavo Niemeyer Google Aims at Bootstrapping Go 1.5 Gopher Gala Submissions (Gift by Scott Brooks) Edmonton Go Workshop Photos Jobs Trumpet in Calgary, AB Articles Errors Errors Are Values by Rob Pike Error Handling In Go by William Kennedy Concurrent Error Handling by John Schaeffer Errors and Exceptions, redux by Dave Cheney Opinion Why Tech Startups Should Look At Go by William Kennedy Golang is Trash by Keith Wesolowski Comparing Go and .</description></item><item><title>Weekend of Go</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/wog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/wog/</guid><description>Gopher Gala Giant Gopher Cake Designed by Renee French Gopher Gala is a distributed 48-hour hackathon for the Go programming language. Register and build something awesome!
You can fly solo or form a team of up to four people. To hack from Startup Edmonton, you can also register here. Startup Edmonton will be open the full 48 hours. Things kick off Friday, January 23 at 6pm and go until Sunday at 6pm.</description></item><item><title>December 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-12/</guid><description>Food at 6:30 pm. Video at 7:00.
Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Movie Night Best Practices for Production Environments by Peter Bourgon A Channel Compendium by John Graham-Cumming Matthias baked this giant gopher cake for our belated Five Years of Go celebration.
News Go 1.4 A Tour of Go: a fresh new version Articles Generating code by Rob Pike Go 1.4 runtime visualized by Mike Perham Code of Ages by Scott Rosenberg Go: Best Practices for Production Environments by Peter Bourgon Five suggestions for setting up a Go project by Dave Cheney Managing Dependencies by Nathan Youngman Advent 2014 series Events Monthly Hackathon - January 10 Go Workshop - January 24 GopherCon India - February 19-21 GopherCon 2015 - July 8-9 at the Colorado Convention Center Edmonton Go Meetup - January</description></item><item><title>November 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-11/</guid><description>Pizza at 6:30 pm. Talks at 7:00.
Please RSVP at Meetup or Google+.
Talks (Go 1.4) Code generation in Go Matthias Stone
Go on Android Prateek Srivastava
News Half a decade with Go Go 1.4 Release Candidate 1 Go is moving to GitHub HTTP/2 demo Earlier bird tickets for Edmonton Go Workshop Articles Birthday Bash series Error Handling In Go, Part I and Part II by William Kennedy Events Wednesday Hack Nights - November 26 Monthly Hackathon - December 6 Go Workshop - January 24 GopherCon India - February 19-21 GopherCon 2015 - July 8-9 at the Colorado Convention Center Edmonton Go Meetup - December</description></item><item><title>October 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-10/</guid><description>We get started at 6:30 pm.
Pizza provided. Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
Talks Using Hugo Nathan Youngman
Hugo is a fast and modern static website engine written in Go. Use it to for your blog or website.
I came for the easy concurrency, I stayed for the easy composition John Graham-Cumming
A talk from dotGo (video, source)
The Go Standard Library Daniel Huckstep
Daniel Huckstep is the author of Go, The Standard Library.</description></item><item><title>September 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-09/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
We get started at 6:30 pm, pizza is provided.
Talks Docker @fnichol
Docker has been taking the cloud by storm. Come learn about containers and distributed applications. (slides)
Related:
Why Did Docker Catch on Quickly and Why is it so Interesting? Docker closes $40M Series C funding HTML Templates @MatthiasStone
Building on the introduction to text/template from June, Matthias will show us how to use the HTML template facilities that come with the Go standard library.</description></item><item><title>August 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-08/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
Hack Night Bring your laptop. Pair up and control a Sphero using Go. We&amp;rsquo;re building a multi-player zombie game with Gobot. (slides, code)
6:30pm Devour the provided pizza. 7:00pm Program room for a short presentation. 7:20pm Form teams and setup around the Sphero arena. Sphero Future of Playtime (video) Happy accident: Sphero makes the move from toy to teaching Online Talks The State of Go by Andrew Gerrand Why We Use Go at Apcera by Derek Collison Testing Techniques by Andrew Gerrand &amp;ldquo;Lexical Scanning in Go&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Cuddle: an App Engine Demo&amp;rdquo; More at GopherVids Resources The Go Programming Language Gopher Community on Slack Job board at golangprojects.</description></item><item><title>July 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-07/</guid><description>Pizza provided (at 6:30 pm). Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
Talks Hello Go Bring your laptop. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re using Atom, Sublime Text or vim on Linux, Mac or Windows, we&amp;rsquo;ll help everyone get setup with a productive Go environment. If you already have the perfect setup, come help those who don&amp;rsquo;t. (slides, source)
Movie Night Be inspired. Stay to watch Go for gophers by Andrew Gerrand (video, slides).
Jobs Senior QA Engineer at Cisco in Calgary.</description></item><item><title>June 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-06/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
Talks Go Templates @MatthiasStone
Code Reading: encoding/csv (based on Code Club)
News Go 1.3 (golang_cls) Static analysis features of godoc Articles Five things that make Go fast Reasons Why a Functional Programmer Might Embrace Go Go’s Context Aware HTML Templates The Go Templates Post From Node.js To Go, Why One Startup Made The Switch Go, REST APIs, and Pointers GopherCon 2014 Wrap Up Online Talks From Parallel to Concurrent GopherCon videos and slides Resources Gopher Community on Slack Job board at golangprojects.</description></item><item><title>May 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-05/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
Pizza sponsored by AGiLE ANiMAL.
Talks Reflection Daniel Huckstep (code, more code) Contributing to Go Nathan Youngman (slides) Building Database Applications with database/sql (video, slides) Baron Schwartz News GopherCon videos and slides Gopher Community on Slack Go 1.3 beta 2 (golang_cls) Job board at golangprojects.com (Twitter) More news at Golang Weekly and Newspaper.IO Tools GoCover.io Articles A Comparison of Go Web Frameworks Go: Best Practices for Production Environments Go, Robots and Code Refactoring Intro++ to Go Interfaces Go&amp;rsquo;s power is in emergent behavior My Thoughts on Martini Go 1.</description></item><item><title>April 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-04/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+. Pizza provided.
Talks Testing Go Web Applications - HTTP &amp;amp; SQL @MatthiasStone
A look at the httptest and sqlmock packages.
Generic Map @abramh (video)
A lecture on a generic map function in Go.
GopherCon @fnichol, @nathany
Highlights from the conference.
News Go, Martini and Gophercasts with Jeremy Saenz Changelog podcast #117 GopherCon talks GCC 4.9 includes Go 1.2.1 Job board at golangprojects.com (Twitter) More news at Golang Weekly and Newspaper.</description></item><item><title>March 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-03/</guid><description>Please RSVP at Meetup and/or Google+.
Talks Testing in Go: What You Need to Know @MatthiasStone (code)
A walk through Go&amp;rsquo;s testing package and how it differs from third-party assertion frameworks.
Composition &amp;amp; Delegation @nathany (code)
Embedding provides a clean way to delegate to member objects. We&amp;rsquo;ll also discuss Go&amp;rsquo;s emphasis on composition.
Go&amp;#39;s Secret C Interface @darkhelmetlive (code)
How to write functions in C and call them from Go without requiring cgo.</description></item><item><title>February 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-02/</guid><description>Please RSVP. Pizza to be provided by Jobber.
Talks Duck Hunt: Interfaces @nathany (code)
&amp;ldquo;If it quacks like a duck&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; exploring interfaces in Go.
This talk builds on last month&amp;rsquo;s talk on types &amp;amp; methods. If you missed it, you may wish to watch the screencast.
Iteration in Go @abramh (video, code &amp;amp; slides)
Iterating all the things.
News &amp;amp; Events Drone and Docker, Open Source CI Go Style Guide Toward Go 1.</description></item><item><title>January 2014 Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2014-01/</guid><description>Talks Celsius: Types Are Cool @nathany (video, code)
We will refactor some procedural code, learning how to use types and methods in Go.
This talk is suitable for programmers new to the Go language.
Concurrency Is Not Parallelism @rob_pike (video, slides, code)
Concurrency is a way of structuring code that can enable parallel execution. After a number of seemingly silly examples, Rob Pike wraps up with a complete load balancer written in Go.</description></item></channel></rss>