<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 on Edmonton Go</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 on Edmonton Go</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February 2022 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2022-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2022-02/</guid><description>Meetup #74. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Online Meeting at 6:30pm MST.
Agenda Go 1.18 New Feature: Generics Peter Preeper reviews new awaited feature of Generics
Future Topics Discussion Open discussion on topic for future talks, workshops, activities.
News golangweekly.com latest Articles &amp;amp; Resources What&amp;rsquo;s Coming in Go 1.18 Video: Getting Started with Generics in Go Go Generics for the Busy Gopher Events Edmonton Go Meetup - March</description></item><item><title>April 2021 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-04/</guid><description>Meetup #73. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Talks Google Cloud Functions Matthias Stone will be presenting on basic practices of creating Google Cloud Functions in Go. (slides)
News Golang Weekly Edmonton Go Meetup - February 2022</description></item><item><title>February 2021 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-02/</guid><description>Meetup #71. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Error Handling discussion Peter Preeper will be walking us through the changes to the errors package introduced in Go 1.13. We&amp;rsquo;ll be watching Can We Panic Yet? Error Handling in Go as a group. Discussion to follow. News Go 1.16 is released Golang Weekly Events Edmonton Go Meetup - April</description></item><item><title>January 2021 Online Meetup</title><link>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edmontongo.org/meetup/2021-01/</guid><description>Meetup #70. Please RSVP at Meetup.
We will be meeting online using this Google Meet at 6:30pm MST.
Talks Four Go-to Packages Matthias Stone (slides)
Open Mic Anyone can feel free to share something they are working on or learning that is related to the Go programming language.
News GopherCon 2020 videos Can We Panic Yet? Error Handling in Go Command PATH security in Go A Proposal for Adding Generics to Go Go on ARM and Beyond Golang Weekly Events Edmonton Go Meetup - February</description></item></channel></rss>